It turns out the correct answer is actually Kimberli.
正确答案其实是 Kimberli
But why? Let's trace the program and see.
为什么呢？ 我们来跟踪程序 看看是怎么回事
The first thing we do, is we create and initialize this variable size using names.length.
首先创建这个变量 size 并将其初始化为 names. length
In this case, the size is actually seven.
因此 size 值为 7
Then we create this variable longestName and we initialize it to names of zero,
然后创建这个变量 longestName 将其初始化为 names [0]
which is this value here.
也就是这个值
So longestName becomes Anja.
所以 longestName 变为 Anja
Then we start our for loop
然后创建 for 循环
initializing i to one.
将 i 初始化为 1
And as long as i is less than size, and then we increment by i++.
然后条件是 i 小于 size 增量为 i++
So inside our loop, we check if name of i the length is greater than longestName.length.
所以在循环里 我们会判断 names [i].length 是否大于 longestName.length
Names of I in
names [i]
this particular point is Kimberli and longestName is Anja.
在这个时候是 Kimberli 而 longestName 是 Anja
This happensaaa to be eight characters long and this is only four,
这个是 8 个字符长度 而这个只有 4 个
so this if statement is true.
所以这个 if 语句为真
names[i].length, which is eight is greater than longestName.length, which is four.
为 8 的 names[i].length 比为 4 的 longestName.length 大
So we step inside the if condition and we update
所以我们进入 if 条件
longest name to be equal to names, which is Kimberli.
将 longestName 的值更新为 names 的 也就是更新为 Kimberli
We move on adding one to i.
我们继续 给 i 加 1
So we're Know checking Edmond,
现在来判断 Edmond
we do our comparison.
进行比较
Edmond's only six characters long compared to eight,
Edmond 只有 6 个字符长度 和 8 比的话
so we do not step into the if condition and we just keep going.
我们就不用进入 if 条件里了 继续循环就好
Then we compare Shenna,
比较 Shenna
which is also six characters long,
这也是 6 个字符长
so it's not greater than Kimberli.
并不比 Kimberli 大
So this if statement is false we do not update longestName and we keep going.
所以 if 条件为假 我们不需要更新 longestName 继续就好
Now reach Apolonia, which is eight characters long.
现在到了 Apolonia 它有 8 个字符长
So our if statement is saying if names of i, which is Apolonia.length,
而我们的 if 条件说的是 如果 names [i] 也就是 Apolonia.length
which happens to be eight is greater than longestName.length,
也就是 8 比 longestName.length 大
which is Kimberli.length, which is eight.
后者指的是 Kimberli.length 值为 8
So it's saying if eight is greater than eight, that's not true.
因此条件说的是如果 8 大于 8 所以条件非真
Eight is not greater than eight,
因为 8 不大于 8
so we do not step into this statement and hence we do not update the longest name.
所以我们不进入这个语句 因此不更新 longestName
So longestName remains Kimberli and then we continue
所以 longestName 依然为 Kimberli 我们继续循环
our loop where the remaining two strings are also smaller than Kimberli.
剩下的两个字符串都比 Kimberli 小
So, by the end of our loop we return the longestName which still has Kimberli in it.
所以结束循环后 我们返回出的 longestName 值仍为 Kimberli
And that's why, in this particular implementation,
这就是为什么在这个实现过程中
this example would actually return Kimberli.
这个案例实际上会返回 Kimberli
In a general sense,
概括地说
It would return the first longest string it finds.
程序会返回出它找到的第一个最长字符串
However, another correct implementation of this function could be,
不过 这个函数还有另一种实现的可能
this check here greater than or equal to.
那就是这个判断 大于或等于
Let's trace this one and see what this would return.
我们来跟踪这个 看看它会返回什么结果
longestName would be initialized to Anja again,
longestName 会再次被初始化为 Anja
and then in our loop we start moving down to Kimberli,
在循环里 我们向下来到 Kimberli
which is greater than Anja.
该字符串比 Anja 长
So, we update that and then we step down again to Edmond,
所以我们把 Anja 更新掉 再次向下来到 Edmond
it's not greater than Kimberli so we just skip that one.
比 Kimberli 小 所以跳过这个
Shenna is also not greater than Kimberli so we skip that one.
Shenna 也还是比 Kimberli 小 所以也跳掉
And now Apolonia is eight, Kimberli is eight,
现在是 Apolonia 为 8 Kimberli 也为 8
so where condition is if eight is greater than or equal to eight,
所以我们的条件现在是如果 8 大于或等于 8
which is true in this case,
为真
so we step inside and we update longestName to names of i, which is Apolonia.
所以进入 if 语句内部 更新 longestName 为 names [i] 的值 也就是 Apolonia
So longestName gets updated to Apolonia this time.
所以这一次 longestName 更新成了 Apolonia
And then we step through Caroll,
接着判断 Caroll
and the last name which are both smaller than Apolonia.
以及最后一个名字 都比 Apolonia 小
So we end up returning that longestName,
所以最后我们返回出的 longestName
which is this one this time.
变成了这个
So a small difference like this check, between greater than,
所以一个小小的变化 就像这个判断
or greater than or equal can make this subtle difference.
从大于变成了大于或等于 就会造成这么点不同